Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
Furidashita
And the raindrops
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
Mada minu sekai e
This is the bullet used in the murder of Brigadier General Hughes.
.45 caliber, and only one shot was fired.
I'd like to say the murderer was skilled, but it was a close proximity shot.
Not impossible for a woman to do.
What is the caliber of your gun?
.45.
This is your ammunition request application.
Am I right?
It's written here you only needed to be supplied with one shot.
What did you use it for?
As it says right there,
I used it at Research Laboratory 5, while I escorted Edward Elric...
But Research Laboratory 5 is closed down, and there shouldn't be anyone there.
But there were.
...According to you.
Should I order a search for this bullet you supposedly shot?
Research Laboratory 5 is in ruins now due to an unknown explosion.
So the place where you say you used
your gun is usually unvisited by people,
and even if we wanted to search for
the bullet, it'd be under a heap of rubble...
There's witness testimony stating you left the scene of the crime, on the exact date and time it occurred.
That's ridiculous!
Compose yourself.
What were you doing at the time?
I was on leave that day and at my parents' house.
You can confirm with them.
Testimony from family members or people whom you are close with cannot be accepted as an alibi.
Second Lieutenant Maria Ross is currently being interrogated.
Though you may be her superior, I cannot allow you to see her.
I see...
Major Armstrong!
Sergeant Brosh.
You were here, too, Major?
Yeah. Are you here for Second Lieutenant Ross?
Yes. The truth is-
The truth is, like the lieutenant, I also fired one round at Research Laboratory 5 while escorting the Elric Brothers.
What?
I reported that, but they didn't listen at all.
So they're planning on passing her off as the murderer?
Cold Flame
Now that I look closely, you're really scratched up.
Not an easy journey, huh?
Say, what are you going to do now?
Hey...
I wonder...
Mama, don't cry.
What do you want me to do?
What?
No, it's just that you've never asked me for advice about something concerning yourselves...
Oh...
It really scares me.
Both of you are fighting in a place so dangerous that Mr. Hughes was killed.
I got really scared when I thought about that.
Because... you both could die.
And suddenly disappear from my side.
Just like Mom and Dad...
I got really scared when I thought about that.
To be honest, I want you to end your journey.
I want you two to get your bodies back.
But I don't want you to go on any dangerous journeys.
Because...
But...
Sorry.
I don't really know what I want either.
You're really kind, Winry.
Huh?! W-W-What are you saying?
I'm always kind!
Stop! You're going to scratch me up even more!
PLACEHOLDER
Geez Al, what are you saying?
There.
Evening paper!
Finally!
What, the paper again?
I'm forced to watch over you all day.
This is about the only thing I can look forward to.
Warrant Officer Falman speaking. I'm calling from an outside line.
Please put me through to Colonel Mustang.
That's right. My code is...
What's the deal?
Airam, George, Oliver, 4649.
It's that lady from back then!
Philosopher's stones...
Ones who have tattoos of Ouroboros...
Homunculus...
How are they...
Brother!
Look at this...
Don't scare me like that.
I... got this from the front desk!
What is it?
What?!
"Second Lieutenant Maria Ross convicted on charges of the murder of Brigadier General Hughes"?!
I don't believe this.
Maybe the colonel or the major might know something.
Aren't you going to tell Winry?
I'll explain it to her later.
I don't like this thing.
Quit complaining. It's kind of like a collar for a dog.
Oh, and I'm going to ask again just to be sure...
Are you really fifteen?
Yeah.
Stop lying.
But it's true...
What's all this?
What's going on?
An intruder!
Please lend us a hand!
What?!
You'd better behave!
Yes, sir!
Weak, weak, weak!
Are you guys even trying?!
What's with this guy?!
Guns aren't working at all!
Move!
You-
Whoa!
But it's awfully boring not being allowed to cut them.
Hello! Guy who's not affected by guns!
Could you let me out of here?
Who are you?
An illegal alien from Xing.
Oh, I see.
Must have been a long trip.
I'll help you if you let me out!
I don't have time to mess around with you...
What country did you say you're from?
Xing of the East.
Come with me.
Thanks.
What?
Hello, Honey!
I've finally found you!
You were at Research Laboratory 5-
I'm glad you remember me.
I think of you every time I see the hole in my right hand you shot through.
Ms. Murderer of Hughes.
That's a misunderstanding!
Is it really?
The paper says it's confirmed.
No way...
At this rate, it looks like you're going to have the guilt pinned on you and get executed by a firing squad.
You're kidding...
There's no way... If they investigate thoroughly-
Make a decision!
Get tortured to death by these guys or escape with me!
Those are the two choices you've got!
That's horrible...
Are those the only choices available?
Looks that way.
God, damn it!
Mom, Dad, I'm sorry!
Fine, I'll escape. Happy?
You'd better escort me, you stupid bone armor!
Wow, you've got spunk.
Women have to have guts!
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
Notify the entire city.
Maria Ross has escaped from jail.
She's with a fiendish partner. Capture her immediately.
If she resists...
...don't hesitate to kill her!
How much longer are we going to run?!
Shut up and keep running!
Second Lieutenant Ross?!
Edward! Alphonse!
Hey! You're that guy from-
And Ling, too?!
Hiya!
What are you guys up to?
That's what we should be asking!
We don't have much time!
You...
Lady, go straight down that alley to reach the warehouse district!
It's dark enough over there to make your escape!
Second Lieutenant Ross, about Lt. Colonel Hughes...
Hurry up! If the military police finds you, they'll shoot you dead!
Second Lieutenant Ross!
Don't follow her!
Second Lieutenant!
Second Lieutenant Ross!
You're Maria Ross, right?
What?!
Oh, so she did it?
Hey!
Hold it!
Whoa!
We're going, thin-eyes!
You got it!
Ling! Why are you working with a guy like that?!
We'll talk later!
Seriously...
Yo, Fullmetal.
What's the meaning of this...
What's the meaning of this, Colonel?!
Why...
Lt. Colonel Hughes was...
Why would Second Lieutenant Ross...
Why didn't you tell me in the first place?!
Attacking a superior?
Know your place!
You can't, Brother!
Let go of me, Al!
No!
This bastard just killed Second Lieutenant Ross!
Second Lieutenant Ross?
What is this, Colonel?!
There was a kill-on-sight order issued for Maria Ross, an escaped convict.
That's all there is to it.
"That's all"?!
I do apologize for hiding Hughes' death.
But do not object to orders. Do not seek explanation.
Simply obey.
That's what it means to be a soldier!
Colonel Mustang.
Explain the situation to me.
There should have been a notice issued saying if she resists, we could gun her down.
She resisted, so I killed her.
The Brigadier General was a good friend of yours from what I hear.
Yeah.
He was a good man.
It weren't your men who helped
Second Lieutenant Ross escape from jail, right?
Mine?
Why would I?
Why?
So you could burn her to death like that yourself.
I'd appreciate it if you didn't make assumptions.
I'm truly sorry for not telling you about Brigadier General Hughes' death.
Because of me...
Don't brood over it.
It is not your fault.
So you're all here.
Dr. Nox...
The damage is extensive.
But from a scar on her tooth that was just narrowly left unscathed, we were able to identify her as Maria Ross.
How horrible.
Turning a babe like that into charcoal.
You must have really had something against her, eh, Mr. Mustang?
Are you satisfied you were able to avenge your friend's death?
It makes me sick a hero from the Ishbal War
would go so far against a little girl.
Colonel, I can't express to you how sorry I am for what my subordinate did.
I had no idea Second Lieutenant Ross would murder...
She's always been honest... hardworking...
And thoughtful...
Looks like you're exhausted, Major.
Why not take a vacation?
Eastern Headquarters, where I used to be stationed, was great.
It lacks the bustle of large cities,
and most of all, there are so many beauties.
And so, Mustang was able to avenge his best friend.
And everyone lived happily ever after.
You petered out.
Wasn't the purpose of this mission to make the colonel behave?
Who cares?
The dog ate its bait.
And it seems he's provoking people's antipathy.
His own men may even be disgusted at him.
What's this?
Request for leave.
At this time of the year?
Is something wrong?
No, it's fine. I permit it.
Thank you very much.
Oh, for crying out loud!
Why did you leave this place?! There's no knowing what the colonel will say to me if he finds out!
No one saw me coming back.
That's not the problem here!
You're a poor soldier that's in the hands of a vicious criminal, so it's okay.
Huh?!
Yo, what are you doing?
Sending a signal.
Signal?
And besides, why did you bring back some random stranger?!
Young Master! We've looked all over for you!
Oh wow, that was quick.
More guests.
Hey Elizabeth! How are you?
Thanks for calling all the time.
But won't your scary aide scold you if you slack off too much?
It's all right! She's on leave right now.
Which is why I can call you like this.
What do you think?
This starts as soon as the lieutenant goes on vacation.
I guess she really was...
...His babysitter...
That's right!
I haven't had any days off since I came here.
So I'm thinking about taking a holiday soon.
Oh? Going somewhere?
I've gotten into fishing lately.
Want to come along?
Yes?
Who is it-
Why did you do that all of a sudden, Major?!
Edward Elric.
Oh no.
Your automail is broken.
Huh?
Yes. This is a serious situation.
We must get it fixed right away.
I'll escort you to Resembool.
Well, umm...
What? What?
We're going back to Resembool?
Al, listen to this...
Alphonse Elric, you stick out too much, so stay in Central.
All right! Let's make arrangements for the train ride.
Let's go, Edward Elric!
Can you cut it out already, Major?
No can do.
This is also an order.
From that man...
Yes, I understand.
Major Armstrong and Edward Elric just got on a train.
I see.
Now there are no hindrances.
I was able to come in contact with a witness who saw the guy who assaulted the prison.
And this is what he looks like.
Oh, he was alive?
I wonder if he has anything to do with the Flame Colonel?
Who knows?
But I think we can say for sure that there is a big possibility.
Where did he run off to?
Well, he's speedy, and to top it off,
he's also good at hiding...
So in other words, you don't know?
You're so incompetent.
Shut up, hag.
We don't have enough people, that's why.
People?
He's all we need.
You're up, Barry the Chopper.
I don't have to act tough, right?
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
The whole truth lies in Xerxes.
The residents left in the city that rusted away and disappeared...
...wipe away the darkness within the boy.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
The Arrogant Palm
of a Small Human
Episode 18, The Arrogant Palm of a Small Human.
Humans, raise the signal of counterattack.